# Yifan Gao

Rm 1024, Ho Sin-Hang Engineering Building The Chinese University of Hong Kong Shatin N.T. Hong Kong Email: yifangao95@gmail.com Web: https://yifan-gao.github.io/ Google Scholar LinkedIn Github

**RESEARCH INTERESTS**: My research interests are in natural language processing and machine learning. My research goal is to enable machines to assist information gathering and knowledge testing through natural language interactions. Recently I work on conversational question answering, open-domain dialogue generation and question generation.

## **EDUCATION**

# The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Aug 2017 - Present

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science & Engineering Advisors: Prof. Irwin King, Prof. Michael R. Lyu

## Technische Universität Darmstadt

Sep 2016 - Feb 2017

Exchange Student in Computer Science

## **Beihang University**

Aug 2013 - Jul 2017

B.Eng. in Electronic & Information Engineering

## **EXPERIENCES**

Research Intern, Salesforce Research, Singapore

Oct 2019 - Jan 2020

Worked with Chien-Sheng Wu, Shafiq Joty and Steven Hoi on Conversational Machine Reading Ranked 1st on the ShARC Conversational Machine Reading Challenge (Nov 2019)

Research Intern, Tencent AI Lab, Shenzhen, China

May 2018 - Aug 2019

Worked with Lidong Bing and Piji Li on Question Generation for Question Answering

## **PUBLICATIONS & PREPRINTS**

ACL'20 Explicit Memory Tracker with Coarse-to-Fine Reasoning for Conversational Machine Reading.

**Yifan Gao**, Chien-Sheng Wu, Shafiq Joty, Caiming Xiong, Richard Socher, Irwin King, Michael R. Lyu, Steven C.H. Hoi. To appear in Proceedings of the 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. Seattle, Washington, USA, July 5-10, 2020.

EMNLP'19 Improving Question Generation With to the Point Context.

Jingjing Li\*, **Yifan Gao**\*, Lidong Bing, Irwin King, Michael R. Lyu. Proceedings of the 2019 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and the 9th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing. Pages 3214–3224, Hong Kong, China, November 3-7, 2019. (\* indicates equal contribution)

ACL'19 Interconnected Question Generation with Coreference Alignment and Conversation Flow Modeling.

Yifan Gao, Piji Li, Irwin King, Michael R. Lyu. Proceedings of the 57th Annual Meeting

of the Association for Computational Linguistics. Pages 4853–4862, Florence, Italy, July 28 - August 2, 2019.

IJCAI'19 Difficulty Controllable Generation of Reading Comprehension Questions.

**Yifan Gao**, Lidong Bing, Wang Chen, Irwin King, Michael R. Lyu. Proceedings of the 28th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence. Main track. Pages 4968-4974, Macao, China, August 10-16, 2019.

AAAI'19 Generating Distractors for Reading Comprehension Questions from Real Examinations.

**Yifan Gao**, Lidong Bing, Piji Li, Irwin King and Michael R. Lyu. The 33rd Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Conference on Artificial Intelligence. Pages 6423-6430, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, January 27 - February 1, 2019.

AAAI'19 Title-Guided Encoding for Keyphrase Generation.

Wang Chen, **Yifan Gao**, Jiani Zhang, Irwin King, Michael R. Lyu. The 33rd Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Conference on Artificial Intelligence. Pages 6268-6275, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, January 27 - February 1, 2019.

2017 Learning Multi-level Features For Sensor-based Human Action Recognition.
Yan Xu, Zhengyang Shen, Xin Zhang, Yifan Gao, Shujian Deng, Yipei Wang, Yubo Fan,
Eric I-Chao Chang. Pervasive and Mobile Computing Journal 40 (2017): 324-338.

## **AWARDS AND HONORS**

2017-2021 Postgraduate Studentship, The Chinese University of Hong Kong
 2014 National Scholarship, Ministry of Education of the P.R. China

#### PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

**Program Committee Member**, The 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP-20)

**Program Committee Member**, The 28th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING-20)

**Program Committee Member**, The 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL-20)

Program Committee Member, The 37th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML-20)

**Program Committee Member**, The 34th Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-20)

**Program Committee Member**, The 2020 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN-2020)

**Program Committee Member**, The 33rd Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-19)

**Program Committee Member**, The 2018 IEEE/ACM International Conference on. Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining

**Secondary Reviewer**, The 2019 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and 9th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing (EMNLP-IJCNLP-19)